To better understand how Agile differs from a traditional approach,
let's take a look at two teams working toward the same product.
A specialty retailer wants to build an app
that helps a customer choose the best sunglasses.
Both teams determined that there will be three features,
including taking photos of users, matching photos to sunglasses inventory,
and purchasing the sunglasses.
Teams have three months to build and launch the app.
The traditional team is going to use a sequential process.
They will complete each stage before moving to the next step.
So, after identifying features, they will design, then develop, then deploy,
then test and make fixes, and then finally release.
The Agile team is approaching this build based on features.
They will conduct multiple development cycles called sprints
that are one to four weeks each.
For this first sprint, the team is focusing on one feature only:
taking photos.
At the end of the third week, the traditional team is still working
to capture the requirements of the full application, not just the features.
The design is not complete.
The Agile team has the first feature in hand,
and takes it to the store to test with actual customers.
Which is good, because customers shared that, while the app does take photos,
missing is a way to name or identify them.
Without that, it's confusing.
The team will use this feedback to adjust the feature in the next iteration.
Halfway through, the traditional team is heads down in development,
working toward their delivery date.
They're on track and feeling pretty confident.
The Agile team once again takes the app straight to the end user,
the customer, for testing and feedback.
They've now got two features: ability to take photos,
and ability to match them to store inventory.
This time, they'll learn a zooming in capability
that will make the app even more useful.
They noted in the plan to adjust the feature.
At the three-month mark, both teams deliver.
The traditional team is now ready to get the app
in front of the customers and stakeholders.
Their app can indeed take great pictures,
but customers have no way to name the photos they take,
and they can't zoom in or out
to better capture the sunglasses on their faces.
Because the Agile team tested the MVP during each iteration,
they were able to adjust as they built the app.
As a result, they've produced a product the consumer wants:
an app with photo naming functionality, zooming in ability,
and refreshing and erasing picture capability.
Both teams have a working application at the end of three months.
The difference is the Agile team was able to release value all along.
The traditional team only leveraged one feedback loop,
and that feedback came too late.
The Agile team created opportunities to have multiple feedback loops.
The Agile working model is designed to foster collaboration and co-creation,
and to minimize misunderstandings.
Agile means your team will work together in the same room, shoulder to shoulder,
in cross-functional and collaborative teams.
You're all in it together.
Develop a product that is customer-centered.
Build that product iteratively in one to four week durations.
Be empowered to make decisions
and self-organized around how you get the work done.